Guide to the Charles A. Fenton Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Ernest Hemingway Research Material, 1929-1959; Series II; 5.09; (8 boxes)
  - Notes, circa 1955
    - Hemingway in Toronto
      - Ralph Connable (Box 27, Folder 453)
      - J. H. Cranston (Box 27, Folder 454)
      - Daily Star (Box 27, Folder 455)
      - H. C. Hindmarsh (Box 27, Folder 456)
      - Star Weekly (Box 27, Folder 457)
    - The Torrents of Spring (1926) (Box 27, Folder 458)
    - Winner Take Nothing (Box 27, Folder 459)
  - Card Files, circa 1955
    - Bibliography (Box 28)
    - Citations, filed chronologically (Box 29)
    - Citations, filed chronologically (continued) (Box 30)
    - Sources, filed alphabetically (Box 28)
- Other Research Material, circa 1955; Series III; 2.5; (6 boxes)
  Organized into four subseries: Writer in America, The National Institute of Arts and Letters, World War II Anthology, and Notes on American Writers.
  Series III. contains Fenton's research notes on the following topics: Writer in America, the history and members of The National Institute of Arts and Letters, Fenton's World War II anthology, and American writers.
  - Writer in America
    - Writer in America (Box 31, Folder 460)
    - 17th Century (Box 31, Folder 461)
    - 18th Century (Box 31, Folder 462)
    - 19th Century (Box 31, Folder 463)
    - 20th Century (Box 31, Folder 464)
    - 1930s (Box 31, Folder 465)
    - Americanism (Box 31, Folder 466)
    - Audience (Box 31, Folder 467)
    - Avant garde (Box 31, Folder 468)
    - Censorship (Box 31, Folder 469)
    - Correspondence (Box 31, Folder 470)
    - Creative Process (Box 31, Folder 471)
    - Economics (Box 31, Folder 472)
    - Editors (Box 31, Folder 473)
    - Exiles (Box 31, Folder 474)
    - Expatriation (Box 31, Folder 475)
    - Foreign Sales, Influence (Box 31, Folder 476)
    - Fraternity (Box 31, Folder 477)
    - Freud (Box 31, Folder 478)
    - Hollywood (Box 31, Folder 479)
    - Magazines (Box 31, Folder 480)
    - Negro (Box 31, Folder 481)
    - New York (Box 31, Folder 482)
    - Politics (Box 31, Folder 483)
    - Publishers (Box 31, Folder 484)
    - Russia (Box 31, Folder 485)
    - Universities (Box 31, Folder 486)
    - War (Box 31, Folder 487)
    - Writer as Teacher (Box 31, Folder 488)
  - National Institute of Arts and Letters
    - Not in / honorary members (Box 32, Folder 489)
    - France / French Academy / foreign members (Box 32, Folder 490)
    - Women (Box 32, Folder 491)
    - Lists of members (Box 32, Folder 492-493)
    - 1930s, including notes on Stephen Vincent Benét (Box 32, Folder 494)
    - Diction (Box 32, Folder 495)
    - Huntington (Box 32, Folder 496)
    - Carnegie (Box 32, Folder 497)
    - World War I (Box 32, Folder 498)
    - N. M. Butler (Box 32, Folder 499)
    - T. R. Roosevelt (Box 32, Folder 500)
    - College Presidents (Box 32, Folder 501)
    - Expatriation (Box 32, Folder 502)
    - 1910s (Box 32, Folder 503)
    - Old Men (Box 32, Folder 504)
    - Magazines / Editors / Sales (Box 32, Folder 505)
    - Historians / American Historical Association (Box 32, Folder 506)
    - Awards (Box 32, Folder 507)
    - Sinclair Lewis (Box 32, Folder 508)
    - Building (Box 32, Folder 509)
    - Laventhol (Box 32, Folder 510)
    - 1920s (Box 33, Folder 511)
    - Emerson (Box 33, Folder 512)
    - Kalkstein (Box 33, Folder 513)
    - 1940s and 1950s (Box 33, Folder 514)
    - [Folder number not used] (Box 33, Folder 515)
    - Awards (Box 33, Folder 516)
  - World War II Anthology
    - World War II Anthology (Box 33, Folder 517)
  - Notes on American Writers
    - Adams, Henry (Box 34, Folder 518)
    - Algren, Nelson (Box 34, Folder 519)
    - Anderson, Sherwood (Box 34, Folder 520)
    - Barton, Ralph (Box 34, Folder 521)
    - Benét, Stephen Vincent (Box 34, Folder 522)
    - Bryant, William Cullen (Box 34, Folder 523)
    - Burns, John Horne (Box 34, Folder 524)
    - Byrd, William (Box 34, Folder 525)
    - Cooper, James Fenimore (Box 34, Folder 526)
    - Crane, Stephen (Box 34, Folder 527)
    - Cummings, E. E. (Box 34, Folder 528)
    - Dickens, Charles (Box 34, Folder 529)
    - Dickenson, Emily (Box 34, Folder 530)
    - Dos Passos, John (Box 34, Folder 531)
    - Dreiser, Theodore (Box 34, Folder 532)
    - Edwards, Jonathan (Box 34, Folder 533)
    - Eliot, T. S. (Box 34, Folder 534)
    - Ellison, Ralph (Box 34, Folder 535)
    - Emerson, Ralph Waldo (Box 34, Folder 536)
    - Farrell, James T. (Box 34, Folder 537)
    - Faulkner, William (Box 34, Folder 538)
    - Fitzgerald, F. Scott (Box 34, Folder 539)
    - Franklin, Benjamin (Box 34, Folder 540)
    - Frost, Robert (Box 34, Folder 541)
    - Gold, Michael (Box 35, Folder 542)
    - Halper, Albert (Box 35, Folder 543)
    - Harte, Bret (Box 35, Folder 544)
    - Hawthorne, Nathaniel (Box 35, Folder 545)
    - Heggen, Thomas (Box 35, Folder 546)
    - Hemingway, Ernest (Box 35, Folder 547)
    - Henry, O. (Box 35, Folder 548)
    - Holmes, Oliver Wendell (Box 35, Folder 549)
    - Irving, Washington (Box 35, Folder 550)
    - James, Henry (Box 35, Folder 551)
    - Jewett, Sarah Orne (Box 35, Folder 552)
    - Johnson, Josephine (Box 35, Folder 553)
    - Jones, James (Box 35, Folder 554)
    - Lardner, Ring (Box 35, Folder 555)
    - Lewis, Sinclair (Box 35, Folder 556)
    - Lindsay, Vachel (Box 35, Folder 557)
    - London, Jack (Box 35, Folder 558)
    - Longfellow, Henry Wadsworth (Box 35, Folder 559)
    - Lowell, James Russell (Box 35, Folder 560)
    - Lowry, Robert (Box 35, Folder 561)
    - McLaughlin, Robert (Box 35, Folder 562)
    - McCullers, Carson (Box 35, Folder 563)
    - Macleish, Archibald (Box 35, Folder 564)
    - Mailer, Norman (Box 35, Folder 565)
    - Masters, Edgar Lee (Box 35, Folder 566)
    - Melville, Herman (Box 36, Folder 567)
    - Mencken, H. L. (Box 36, Folder 568)
    - Michener, James (Box 36, Folder 569)
    - Moody, William Vaughan (Box 36, Folder 570)
    - Newhouse, Edward (Box 36, Folder 571)
    - Norris, Frank (Box 36, Folder 572)
    - O'Hara, John (Box 36, Folder 573)
    - Poe, Edgar Allan (Box 36, Folder 574)
    - Pound, Ezra (Box 36, Folder 575)
    - Puritan. E. Taylor, Bradford, Shepard, Sewall, Bradstreet (Box 36, Folder 576)
    - Ransom, John Crowe and Allen Tate (Box 36, Folder 577)
    - Robinson, E. A. (Box 36, Folder 578)
    - Rolvaag, Ole (Box 36, Folder 579)
    - Salinger, J. D. (Box 36, Folder 580)
    - Sandburg, Carl (Box 36, Folder 581)
    - Shaw, Irwin (Box 36, Folder 582)
    - Short Story, The (Box 36, Folder 583)
    - Sinclair, Upton (Box 36, Folder 584)
    - Stegner, Wallace (Box 36, Folder 585)
    - Stein, Gertrude (Box 36, Folder 586)
    - Steinbeck, John (Box 36, Folder 587)
    - Stiles, Bert (Box 36, Folder 588)
    - Styron, William (Box 36, Folder 589)
    - Thoreau, Henry David (Box 36, Folder 590)
    - Twain, Mark (Box 36, Folder 591)
    - West, Nathaniel (Box 36, Folder 592)
    - Wharton, Edith (Box 36, Folder 593)
    - Whitman, Walt (Box 36, Folder 594)
    - Whittier, John Greenleaf (Box 36, Folder 595)
    - Wilson, Sloan (Box 36, Folder 596)
    - Wolfe, Thomas (Box 36, Folder 597)
    - Woolman, John (Box 36, Folder 598)
    - Wright, Richard (Box 36, Folder 599)
- Personal and Professional Papers, 1946-1965; Series IV; 0.84; (2 boxes)
  Not arranged in any particular order.
  Series IV. contains primarily professional papers relating to Fenton's career as a writer and lecturer, as well as a small amount of personal papers and correspondence, and manuscripts.
  - Canadian Air Force discharge papers, 1946-1949 (Box 37, Folder 600)
  - Cowley, Malcolm to CF, 1955-1960 (Box 37, Folder 601)
  - Letters regarding Fenton's World War II anthology, the American Academy and his article in Nation, 1955-1960 (Box 37, Folder 602)
  - John Simon Guggenheim Foundation, application and correspondence, 1957 (Box 37, Folder 603)
  - Writer's Conference, undated (Box 37, Folder 604)
  - Farrar, Straus & Young, Inc., royalty statements and correspondence, 1954-1955 (Box 37, Folder 605)
  - Personal correspondence, 1947-1960 (Box 37, Folder 606)
  - ACLS, undated (Box 37, Folder 607)
  - English 235 #2, 1960 (Box 37, Folder 608)
  - English 351-352, undated (Box 37, Folder 609)
  - English 308x, 1959 (Box 37, Folder 610)
  - English 322 [349], undated (Box 37, Folder 611)
  - English 236, 1960 (Box 37, Folder 612)
  - English Department, 1952-1960 (Box 37, Folder 613-614)
  - English 77, undated (Box 37, Folder 615)
  - English 137-138, 1959 (Box 37, Folder 616)
  - English 165, 1958 (Box 37, Folder 617)
  - English 55, 1960 (Box 37, Folder 618)
  - American Studies 92, 1957 (Box 37, Folder 619)
  - American Studies 59, 1956-1957 (Box 37, Folder 620-621)
  - "It's a Story They Tell," printed in Adventure, 1945 January (Box 37, Folder 622)
  - "The American Man of Letters in the Twentieth Century: A History of the National Institute of Arts and Letters and The American Academy of Arts and Letters, 1898-1958," typescript, corrected, circa 1959 (Box 38, Folder 623-624)
  - "In Our Time: The Craft of Fiction," typescript, corrected, circa 1955 (Box 38, Folder 625)
  - Essays and other short stories, typescript and typescript carbon, corrected, undated (Box 38, Folder 626-627)